<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rachit Singh</title>
    <link>https://rachitsingh.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rachit Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 18:57:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rachitsingh.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Langevin Equation</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/the-langevin-equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 18:57:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/the-langevin-equation/</guid>
      <description>This post covers the Langevin equation, a stochastic differential equation that models the dynamics of particles in Brownian motion 1. This covers the ideas used in this reference due to Lennart Sjögren.
Langevin Equation In 1907 Einstein published a paper that derived a macroscopic quantity \(D\), the diffusion constant, with microscopic quantities:
\[D = \frac{k_BT}{6\pi\eta a}\]
where \(\eta\) is the viscosity of the liquid and \(a\) is the radius of the particle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistence Length</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/persistence-length/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 10:52:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/persistence-length/</guid>
      <description>td { padding: 5px; font-family: monospace; font-size: 1.25rem; } th { text-align: center; padding: 0px 5px; } th.left_column { text-align: right; } figure { margin: 0px 20px; max-width: 50rem; } img[src*=&#34;#smaller&#34;] { width: 65%; margin: auto; margin-bottom: 15px; }  In class we recently discussed the simplified elastic rod model for polymers, which assumes that polymers can be modeled as an inextensible rod, i.e. that the length of the rod doesn&#39;t change, and that the twist of the polymer is ignorable (possibly because the polymer is joined by single bonds).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few favorite papers of 2017</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/a-few-favorite-papers-of-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:48:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/a-few-favorite-papers-of-2017/</guid>
      <description>This isn&#39;t an exhaustive list, and I will inevitably forget some papers. I&#39;ll keep updating as a remember, and will probably expand some of the background/contribution sections as I have time, so that they&#39;re more accessible.
Breaking the Softmax Bottleneck: A High-Rank RNN Language Model [link] Background: Language models and NLP tasks almost always use a softmax to compute a distribution over the vocabulary, and usually this is computed as \(\sigma(\mathbf{W}\mathbf{h})\), where \(\mathbf{h}\) is a \(d\)-dimensional context vector from a previous layer, and \(\mathbf{W} \in \mathbb{R}^{M \times d}\) is a word embedding, letting $M$ be the vocabulary size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch Internals, cuRAND, and numerical instability</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/pytorch-internals-curand-and-numerical-instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 18:44:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/pytorch-internals-curand-and-numerical-instability/</guid>
      <description>Random sampling I&#39;ve been working lately to implement random samplers from a number of distributions in PyTorch, both on CPU and CUDA. This is a topic near and dear to my heart, since it has caused me a lot of trouble multiple times. Once this PR is merged, I&#39;ll post an explanation/notebook of why this is important.
Here&#39;s a brief summary of the motivation:
 We want to sample from distributions like \(\operatorname{Beta}(a, b)\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ELBO Surgery</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/elbo_surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 12:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/elbo_surgery/</guid>
      <description>td { padding: 5px; font-family: monospace; font-size: 1.25rem; } th { text-align: center; padding: 0px 5px; } th.left_column { text-align: right; } figure { margin: 0px 20px; max-width: 50rem; } img[src*=&#34;#smaller&#34;] { width: 50%; margin: auto; }  tldr: The ubiquitous isotropic Gaussian prior for generative models doesn&#39;t make sense / doesn&#39;t work, which motivates work on priors.
At NIPS, Dawen Liang mentioned Hoffman &amp;amp; Johnson&#39;s ELBO surgery paper offhand while talking about tuning KL divergences, and it&#39;s very interesting, so I thought I&#39;d go over it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIPS 2017</title>
      <link>https://rachitsingh.com/nips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:47:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rachitsingh.com/nips/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m starting this blog to share research ideas that I have, and some solutions to problems I find along the way. I&#39;ve been helped immensely by other people&#39;s blogs in the past, and want to do the same. Also it&#39;ll give me a chance to communicate the way I approach problems, and hopefully people will give me alternative perspectives either by email (rachitsingh@college.harvard.edu) or in the comments, once I figure out how that works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>